Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and what
are we talking about today Marco?
Today we are talking about
a very interesting topic most
importantly among men who
are trying to get women's attention.
Okay, so these are some of the things that
men might try to say if they are trying to
find a girlfriend or men
if you're out there things
that you might want
to say or not want to say.
Right, that's right.
So why don't we just
take a look at our dialogue.
Let's see what's going on
and we'll be back in a bit.
Let's go out tomorrow night. We can go
to a bar and try to find your girlfriend.
I don't think that's a good
idea. I'm just not good
with approaching someone
and starting up a conversation.
Maybe you just need a few pickup
lines, you know, to break the ice.
Pick up lines don't work.
Come on, you can just
walk up to a girl and
say if you were a
booger I'd pick you first.
What? Come on, that's just lame.
No girl would fall for that.
Fine, then you can
say so there you are.
I've been looking all over for
you, the woman of my dreams.
That's a good one.
I think that's pretty funny.
Yeah, so you make her
laugh, you make a fool of
yourself a little bit and
then you buy her a drink.
Okay, how does this sound?
I was so enchanted by your beauty
that I ran into that wall
over there, so I'm going
to need your name and
number for insurance purposes.
Nice, let's go.
All right, we're back. So now let's
explain what's going on a little bit more.
Let's take a look at some
vocab on language takeaway.
So the first word that
we have here Marco is a
verb we say to approach
or to approach someone.
That's right, to approach
someone and that means
to go up to someone
and start a conversation,
start talking to them.
That's right, so you
physically walk towards
someone, you go to them
to start talking to them.
So you can say I'm not
good at approaching other
people or he approached her
in the bar because
he wanted to talk to.
That's right. So to approach
someone is to go up or get
close to that person
and start talking to them.
That's right. All right,
so now what the dialogue
focuses on is pickup lines as the title
says. So what exactly are pickup lines?
All right, well, I'll
take this as a phrase.
You don't want to look
at the individual words,
but pickup lines are
things that people say to
show that they are interested
romantically in other people.
Right. So if I am
talking to someone and
maybe he says something
that is a pickup line,
he's trying to show
that he's interested in
me. That's right. So
usually I guess guys use
pickup lines at bars
or something to get a
girl's attention into as
you say show that he is
interested in her,
right? That's right.
And some are very creative
and nice and some are very
stupid and silly. So
there are many different
kinds of pickup lines.
But the trick here is that
they're usually lines
that the person will
create or will have
heard before they use it.
Right, exactly. It's like
a fixed thing. Uh huh.
Yeah, it is usually very
creative as you say.
You're very funny to kind
of get the girl's attention.
Now, the first pickup
line that we heard
was if you were a
booger, I'd pick you first.
If you were a booger,
I'd pick you first.
All right. So what
does he mean here?
If you were a booger, what is
a booger? A booger is a piece
of dirt in your nose. Okay.
So sometimes you have
some things in your
nose and you want to blow
your nose to clear it.
Well, those things inside
your nose, those
are called boogers.
It's very informal. Right.
So I guess the technical term
for it would be mucus.
Mucus, that's right. But
obviously, in English,
there's also an informal
way of calling it and
it's called a booger.
So the idea here is the pickup
line means two things. It means
sometimes you have to take boogers out
of your nose. Some people use their finger.
But the other meaning
is, you know, if I'm
interested in you, I
would, I pick you first.
Right. Right. And the
verb here to pick is not
to choose, but it's
actually used as a verb,
but when you're talking
about your nose, you pick
your nose or you pick
a booger. That means to
actually remove. It
means to put your finger
in your nose to take
out these pieces of dirt.
Right. So maybe a mom,
a mother to their younger
son or daughter would tell them,
don't pick your nose in public.
Moms often say it's in English.
Don't pick your nose.
It's rude. Exactly. All right.
So it's a very
interesting pickup line.
Obviously, very funny and
it gets creative, but at the
same time, the verb there
to pick, we just figured
out, it means something
completely different.
All right. So it's a joke,
but it's also kind of gross.
Exactly. And obviously
his friend agrees and
says that's lame. Lame.
So something is lame if
it's stupid or not funny.
We often say that's a
really lame joke, which
means I don't like that.
I don't think it's funny.
Okay. And actually, people
start using the word
lame for many things that
they don't like or they
think is not interesting.
Right. Yeah. Like that
band is so lame or that cool.
That movie was lame.
It wasn't interesting.
It wasn't fun. Okay. So
that's basically what it means.
All right. So let's
take a look at
everything we've learned
again and we'll be back in a bit.
Let's go out tomorrow night. We can go
to a bar and try to find your girlfriend.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
I'm just not good with
approaching someone and starting
up a conversation.
Maybe you just need a few
pickup lines, you
know, to break the ice.
Pick up lines. Don't work. Come on.
You can just walk up to a girl and say,
if you were a booger,
I'd pick you first. What?
Come on. That's just lame.
No girl would fall for that.
Fine. Then you can
say, so there you are.
I've been looking all over for
you, the woman of my dreams.
That's a good one. I
think that's pretty funny.
Yeah. So you make
your life. You make a fool
of yourself a little bit
and then you buy a drink.
Okay. How does this
sound? I was so enchanted
by your beauty that I ran
into that wall over there.
So I'm going to need your name and number
for insurance purposes. Nice. Let's go.
All right. Now let's take a look at
some of these phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay. So the first
phrase we have here is something
very, very common
in business as well as in
the social situations.
We say to break the ice.
And this is something
that we heard when the
two boys were talking
about approaching a girl.
Mm-hmm. So I don't
know how to break the ice.
Right. So to break
the ice is to make an
awkward situation or
something that's a little
bit uncomfortable, a
little bit more relaxed.
That's right. So oftentimes
in a new company
or at a party where
you don't know anyone,
you have to break the
ice. You have to make
things more comfortable
so you can talk to people.
That's right. All right. So
you want to break the ice.
You want to maybe be more
comfortable around people.
Right. So sometimes people
use games to break the ice.
Like at your company, maybe your
first day of work, they'll have
games to learn people's names.
These are ways
of breaking the ice.
Or at a party, you learn
some pickup lines to
break the ice with women.
That's right. All right.
So we want to break
the ice. We want to use
some pickup lines. And
his friend argues that
pickup lines are kind of lame. And he
even says no girl would fall for that line.
Okay. To fall for
something, this is a really
important phrase and something
that we say often in English.
Now, what exactly does it mean?
You're not falling on the ground.
No, no. It means you believe
it or you consider
it to be real. All right.
So when something is
a lie or it's fake or it's,
yeah, it's not totally true. But
someone believes it anyway.
You say that that
person, he fell for it.
Okay. So if I say, hey,
Mark, go to do you know
tomorrow's a holiday,
we don't have to work.
Okay. And I don't
come to work. Yeah.
I say, oh, Marco fell for my
trick. I mean, he believed it,
but I was actually
lying. Exactly. All right.
So to fall for something
means to believe it or to
think it's true. Yeah.
So no girl would fall
for that means no girl
would actually like you
because you use
these silly pickup lines.
That's right. All right. So then
he actually used another line.
He said, okay, so maybe
you can use this other line.
And his friend agreed,
okay, that's a good one.
That's a good one. You
can also say good one.
Good one. Yeah. This
is very informal English.
And it's something
that we say when we
want to say that, uh,
you know, I like the idea
or it's a good, it's a
good idea. Or maybe even
a joke, someone tells a joke
and you think it's really funny.
That's a good one.
So in this case, we heard
one good pickup line
and one bad one, but maybe
you're at work and someone
comes up with a really
good idea for marketing,
you say, oh, that's a good
one. That's a good idea.
That's a good one.
That's right. All right.
And obviously his friend
explains that the whole
purpose of the pickup
line is to make a full of
yourself a little bit and
then, you know, buy
the girl the drink or
become her friend.
Okay, to make a full of
yourself. Now, this is something
that is probably not a good
thing in most cases, right?
A full is someone
who is silly, who no one
takes seriously. Right.
Say someone who's not,
yeah, not very serious.
So to make a full of
yourself is to embarrass
yourself a little bit.
Yeah, to look stupid
in front of other people.
So I can say, oh, on
my first day of work,
I tripped and I fell on
the ground and I made
a full of myself in front
of my new colleagues.
That's right. So that's
basically what it means
to make a full of yourself
to embarrass yourself.
But you're doing it
to yourself. It's not that
someone else is embarrassing
you. You are embarrassing yourself.
That's right. All
right. Let's listen to
this dialogue one last time
and we'll be back in a bit.
Let's go out tomorrow night. We can go
to a bar and try to find your girlfriend.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
I'm just not good with approaching
someone and starting up a conversation.
Maybe you just need
a few pickup lines,
you know, to break the
ice. Pick up lines, don't work.
Come on. You can just
walk up to a girl and
say, if you were a
booger, I'd pick you first.
Come on. That's just lame.
No girl would fall for that.
Fine. Then you can
say, so there you are.
I've been looking all over for you.
The woman of my dreams. That's a good one.
I think that's pretty funny.
Yeah. So you make her laugh.
You make a full of yourself a little
bit and then you buy her a drink. Okay.
How does this sound? I was
so enchanted by your beauty
that I ran into
that wall over there.
So I'm going to need your name
and number for insurance purposes.
Nice. Let's go.
All right. So looking
at these pickup lines, we
took a look at the first one
about the booger and everything.
What about the second one?
When you say, so there you are,
I've been looking all over for you.
The woman of my dream.
So what is he saying here?
What is implied?
He's basically saying
that he's met her before
and he's been looking for her.
So where does he mean her?
He says he met her in his
dreams. But now, oh, there she is.
I was looking for you. You're
the woman of my dreams.
Right. So obviously
the girl can feel a little
bit confused at first because
why were you looking for me?
And then he says, oh, because you are
the woman of my dreams. So it's obviously
a little bit exaggerating,
but it's funny.
He's joking, but he's basically
saying, you know, I know you.
I've been looking for you.
And what about our last
pickup line where he was saying,
I was so enchanted by
your beauty that I ran
into that wall over
there. So I am going to
need your name and
number for insurance purposes.
So he's saying,
you're so beautiful
that I had this accident.
I walked into a wall.
I hit my face. Now
that I have an injury,
I need your information
so that I can claim insurance.
So I can get money from
my insurance company.
So this is a way to ask a woman
for her phone number and her name.
And her name exactly.
So it's a very clever way
of obviously breaking
the ice. But at the same
time, he's trying to be
funny and trying to get
her number, her telephone
number and her name.
That's right. So one
of the most memorable
ones that I've heard
was your father, a thief,
because he stole the stars from
the sky and put them in your eyes.
Nice. So this one is
more of a compliment.
Yes, it's a compliment.
And but in a funny way,
saying, oh, your dad stole
all the stars from the sky.
Yeah, no, I've heard
a number of them.
Most of them are
pretty bad, pretty lame.
And they're always a way to
ask for your phone number.
Now, as a girl, what do you think is
better for a guy to use a clever funny,
but tasteful pickup line or to just walk up
to you and say, hi, my name is so-and-so,
you know, what's your
name? If you can be
clever, if you can come
up with something that's
funny or interesting,
then I think it's good.
If you say something
that's rude or disgusting,
I think that's probably
bad, like the booger.
The booger pickup line
is a bad idea, but that's an
example of a bad pickup
line. But you know, if
you can laugh about
it, not you don't say it
seriously, but if you
can laugh about it and
say, hey, you know,
is your daddy a thief,
it's something to start the
conversation if you're laughing.
Right. Because sometimes it's very awkward
to someone says, hey, I'm John, you know,
what's your name? Right.
You don't really know
how to react to
that. It's not boring.
And approaching someone like
that way can be a little bit difficult.
Yeah. It's a very
interesting thing.
Let us know if you
have any pickup lines,
if you've heard any pickup lines of use
any, we're really curious to know. Yeah.
Our website is EnglishPod.com. We hope to
see you guys there. All right, guys. Bye.